After positional encodings,
在学习了位置编码之后
the next most important encoding to know about is color encodings.
下一个重要的编码方式是颜色编码
Color can be used for both qualitative and quantitative values.
分类变量和数值变量都可以用颜色来编码
You've already seen this in the previous lesson.
你在上一节课里已经有看到
Numeric counts were encoded with color and heatmaps,
数值型的计数可以用颜色和热图编码
while categorical labels were encoded with color and clustered bar charts.
分类型的标签可以用颜色和分组条形图编码
Depending on your type of variable,
根据不同的变量类型
you should be inclined to use a different color palette.
你应该选择使用不同的调色板
Here, I'll discuss three major palette types: qualitative, sequential and divergent.
这里我们将重点讲解三种不同的调色板类型：分类的、有序的和发散的
Qualitative palettes are geared towards nominal data.
分类调色板主要面向无序分类变量
These palettes tend to consist of
这种类型的调色板倾向于由不同的色调组成
distinct hues with fairly similar brightness and saturation.
而且这些色调具有非常相似的亮度和饱和度
This way, no ordering is implied and
这样 就不会给受众传达任何颜色有排序的信息
individual levels aren't applied as more important than others.
每个类别之间的重要性也差不多
Sequential palettes should be used for ordinal and numeric data.
有序的调色板则应被用于有序变量和数值变量上
In a good sequential palette,
一个好的有序调色板应该具有以下特点：
low values are indicated by lighter,
较低的值由较浅 较不饱和的颜色表示
less saturated colors, while high values are indicated by darker, more saturated colors.
而较高的值由较暗 较饱和的颜色表示
Sometimes, this is flipped the other way around;
有些时候也会反着来
light for high, and dark for low.
浅的对应大值 暗的对应小值
Usually, a single or small range of hues is used.
这些颜色通常都属于一个色调 或者非常接近的相邻色调
For certain ordinal or numeric data that have a meaningful center point,
对于中心点有意义的某些有序变量和数值变量
a diverging palette can be used.
可以用发散型调色板
A diverging palette is essentially
发散性调色板本质上是
two sequential palettes with distinct hues put back to back,
由两个不同色调的有序型调色板头尾拼接成的
with the connecting color at the center point.
色板中间是拼接颜色
One hue will indicate values greater than the center point,
一个色调代表大于中心点的数据
and the other hue values smaller than the center point.
另一个色调代表小于中心点的数据
There are a couple of things that you should check even
不管选择了哪一种类型的调色板
after selecting a palette, regardless of type.
都需要注意以下几点
First of all, be mindful of hue choice and account for color blindness,
首先 要注意色调选择和色盲问题
especially in qualitative and diverging scales.
特别是在分类和不同的尺度上
If you want to use opposing colors like red and green in the same plot,
如果你想在一个图表上使用互补色 比如红色和绿色
try to make sure that they can be distinguished by
请确保你的图表可以被
those with color perception deficiencies.
色盲患者所识别
The red and green shown on the top are too close in brightness and saturation,
上一排显示的红色和绿色在亮度和饱和度上都太接近
while those on the bottom are more distinct.
下一排这两个颜色则差异性更大
Secondly, try and avoid transparency on top of color.
其次 尽量避免使用透明度
If points of different color overlap,
如果两种不同颜色的数据点重合
this can create uninterpretable new colors.
将会产生新颜色 带来误解或者歧义
If points of the same color but different saturation overlap,
如果颜色相同但饱和度不同的点重合
this can create an altogether new,
也会产生一个全新的颜色
and incorrect value to be perceived.
让受众以为有新的数据